kenkingmukabi@gmail.com (+254 707 231 478) Nairobi Kenya

I am an experienced UI/UX specialist, product designer, graphic designer and a front-End Developer with a proven track record. I am available for Full-time roles, contracts and remote tasks. I design digital products and websites for startups, Brands and entrepreneurs with cool projects. I love fun UI collaboration and design helpful products that people love.

EXPERIENCE

Coinside Betting - Senior UI/UX Designer (Remote)

June 2022 - current / web 3.0 Casino & Sports Betting

- · Researching User Interaction and conducting a series of usability test to determine the optimum UI design.
- Designing mockups, prototypes and templates illustrating the functionalities and appearance of the product.
- Developing a data driven and user focused UX.
- Responsible for all products and UX decisions in the project that is targeted to grow customer base by 300%
- Identify and Troubleshoot UX problems related to layout and responsiveness from Users Reviews.

Fleekingz Lifestyle - Creative Designer (Remote)

June 2022 - current / Lifestyle

- Working on designing Mockups for Fleekingz Lifestyle products, packaging Designs of the Fleekingz cosmetic & Skincare product
- Adhering to the clients standards on Typography, colors and images.

NFadvise Academy - **UI/UX Designer** (Remote)

Jan 2022 – Jun 2022 . 6months / E-learning Platform

 Worked on improving the user experience of an academy's eLearning platform and helped to redesign the courses screen as the sole designer on a team of 2 developers and 2 Project Managers.

Space Ya Tech Community - **UX Designer** (Community Contribution)

Nov 2022 - Jan 2022 . 3months / Community Forum

- Working as part of the community team in developing a platform where African Tech enthusiasts meet, network and share modern challenges in the industry.
- Played a role in research determining target group persona, community brand strategy and ran user tests
- We delivered a comprehensive presentation & a cross functional solution as the product.

Afya Healthcare - **UX Researcher** (Freelance)

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022 . 6months / Healthcare app

• Started with user research interviews and then created the user flow. I identified the uses pain points, users sentiments and the users wishes. Used empathy matrices to come up with a perfect solution used in Ui /UX.

Redbill Brands Africa - web Developer/Designer (Freelance)

Feb 2021 - Oct 2022 . 9months / Developer

• Worked on various design projects for a range of clients. Mainly focused on SMEs, Developed branding, designed collateral websites, a lot of MVPs & UX material for clients. I developed presentation and management skills

Redbill Brands Africa - Junior Designer (Freelance)

Oct 2019 - Jan 2021 . 4months / Developer

• Designed illustrations, Graphic user interface elements (menu, tabs and widgets), Banners, Posters, Social media adverts, Logos, Animations, and other creative designs

I have experience in using the following Design and Development tools

• Figma	 InDesign 	• React
 Adobe XD 	Adobe Premier Pro	 JavaScript
 Adobe Illustrator 	Adobe After Effects	Tailwind CSS
 Adobe Photoshop 	• Anima	 Asana(collaboration)
 Adobe lightroom 	• Framer	 Slack(collaboration)
 Adobe In Design 	• 3D	 Discord(collaboration)
-		

SKILLS

- User Experience Design
- User Interaction Design
- Interactive prototyping
- Graphic Design
- Animation

- Front End Development
- Wireframing
- User Experience Research
- LO-FI /HI-FI Design
- Digital Marketing
- Product Management
- Project Management
- Team player
- Collaborative development

EDUCATION

06/2019 - Present	Btech. Computer Science (Technical University of Kenya)
02/2022 - 03/2022.	IT Support , Google(Coursera) verify:
09/2021 - 02/2022	Project Management , Google (Coursera) verify:
Others	Graphic Designing(self Taught) UI/UX(self Taught) Front End Web Design(self Taught)

ACHIEVEMENTS

I Successfully Delivered 35+ products to clients While working with Redbill Brands Africa.

"Afya App" Case study stood out to be a an award winning products in the industry.

I successfully Mentored 5 cohorts of design Mentees.

I am a Member in a creative design community in Kenya. (Space ya Tech Team Berlin).

Portfolio

https://kennethmukabiportfolio.on.drv.tw/uiuxportfolio/

Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kennethmukabi/